<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Percipio - Blogging</title><link href="https://chriscz.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://chriscz.github.io/feeds/blogging.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://chriscz.github.io/</id><updated>2017-10-04T06:14:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Morning Routine</title><link href="https://chriscz.github.io/morning-routine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-04T06:14:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-04T06:14:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Chris</name></author><id>tag:chriscz.github.io,2017-10-04:/morning-routine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There has been one thing that has carried me through these
last few months, and has prevented a relapse to my morning 
depression - routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to wake up every morning and reflect on the 
many ways that my life has not succeeded and all the
ways the I am …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There has been one thing that has carried me through these
last few months, and has prevented a relapse to my morning 
depression - routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to wake up every morning and reflect on the 
many ways that my life has not succeeded and all the
ways the I am still inferior. These thoughts are pretty automatic,
and there isn't much you can do to stop them from a pure will
perspective. So I tried some apps, the first was one that I had
used a few years prior which helped me start a morning routine:
Fabulous, developed by a &lt;a href="http://advanced-hindsight.com/"&gt;team at Duke University&lt;/a&gt; under the
lead of behavioural economist Dan Ariely which you might remember
from this famous &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_ariely_asks_are_we_in_control_of_our_own_decisions"&gt;Ted talk on the Economist subscription model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then it was useful, right now I didn't even want to get out of bed.
I HAD to make a plan. I set out to use my alarm app &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.urbandroid.sleep&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Sleep as Android&lt;/a&gt;,
and looked at what it had to offer in terms of getting up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had used the captcha solving before, but now needed a stronger dose
of force: The QR Scanner. This scanner supports normal
barcodes, so I set it up to a coffee tin in my kitchen.
Caption: The coffee tin of redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week was especially hard, and
I knew that I had to chain several simple habits together, so I added the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drink a glass of lemon water while in the kitchen, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go back to your room and do some push-ups -- 12 at the least --, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take a shower,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;then meditate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll admit; some days I fucked up as I went out the night before, and 
instead of completing the routine, I would get back in bed and sleep
a few more hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the last 3-4 weeks this has proven to be the most significant change
I've made this year. It has allowed me to do some of the things I 
would usually have to rush, such as my meditation. It 
just makes for a better overall day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now adapted my routine to include some morning contemplations:
Reading Marcus Aurelius's Meditations, and reflecting on 
questions that I have typed for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="routine depression"></category></entry></feed>